Guide to the Hartt School phonograph records ARCH138
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
- Phonograph Recordings, 1938-1986, undated
  - 12-inch Phonograph Records, 1938-1986, undated
    - Levittown Sectional All-State Concert, 1956 Nov 17; 2 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5, Box Record Covers 1)
      Phonograph record of the Levittown Sectional All-State Concert on November 17, 1956 in Levittown, NY. Orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - Humbert Lucarelli, with Gerald Tarack, Thomas Grubb, and the New Art String Trio; Britten, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5)
      Phonograph record of the album Britten released by Lyrichord Stereo (LLST 7195), featuring Humbert Lucarelli (oboe – Hartt faculty), with Gerald Tarack (violin), Thomas Grubb (piano), and the New Art String Trio (with Gerald Tarack – violin, Jean Dupouy – viola, and Alexander Kouguell – cello), performing Benjamin Britten's Six Metamorphoses after Ovid, Opus 49; Suite for Violin and Piano, Opus 6; and Phantasy Quartet, Opus 2.
    - Bert Lucarelli; The Sensual Sound of the Soulful Oboe, 1981; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5)
      Phonograph record of the album The Sensual Sound of the Soulful Oboe: With Guitars, Strings, and Percussion released by Jonella Record Company (JRC-1), featuring Humbert "Bert" Lucarelli (oboe – Hartt faculty).
    - Massachusetts All-State Chorus and Orchestra, 1951 Feb 17; 3 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5)
      Three phonograph records of the Massachusetts All-State Chorus and Orchestra performing on February 17, 1951. Orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - Robert Maxwell; The Broadcaster: A Symphonic Suite, 1961 Nov 27; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 6)
      Phonograph record of The Broadcaster: A Symphonic Suite, composed and conducted by Robert Maxwell on November 27, 1961 for the dedication of Broadcast House (WTIC TV-AM-FM, Hartford, CT) following the unveiling by Governor John N. Dempsey of the bronze statue called "The Broadcaster."
    - NBC; Old Maid and the Thief, 1939 Apr 22; 8 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 6)
      Eight phonograph records of the NBC production of Old Maid and the Thief recorded on April 22, 1939.
    - New England All-State Orchestra, 1956 Mar 24; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 6)
      Phonograph record of the New England All-State Orchestra recorded on March 24, 1956 under the conduction of Moshe Paranov.
    - New England Festival Orchestra and Chorus, 1957 Mar 23; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 6)
      Phonograph record of the New England Festival Orchestra and Chorus recorded on March 23, 1957. Orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - New England Preparatory School Music Festival Chorus, with the Cambridge Festival Orchestra, 1964 Apr; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 6)
      Phonograph record of the New England Preparatory School Music Festival Chorus, with the Cambridge Festival Orchestra, recorded April 1964. Orchestra conducted by Nathan Gottschalk.
    - New York Sectional Orchestra, 1953 Nov 21; 2 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 6)
      Two phonograph records of the New York Sectional Orchestra performing Pop Goes the Weasel and Symphony in F, performed on November 21, 1953.
    - NYSSMA All-State Orchestra, 1951 Nov 17; 2 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 6)
      Two phonograph records of the New York State School Music Association (NYSSMA) All-State Orchestra performing The Last Spring, London Symphony, and Pop Goes the Weasel on November 17, 1951.
    - NYSSMA All-State Orchestra, 1953 Dec 5; 3 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 6)
      Three phonograph records of the New York State School Music Association (NYSSMA) All-State Orchestra performing Pop Goes the Weasel, Farm Journal Suite, Gallop, and The Last String on December 5, 1953.
    - NYSSMA Festival Concert Eastern Division of the Music Educators National Conference, 1965 Feb 4-8; 2 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 6)
      Two phonograph records of the New York State School Music Association (NYSSMA) Festival Concert Eastern Division of the Music Educators National Conference recorded February 4-8, 1965. Orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - NYSSMA Music Festival, 1969; 2 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 6)
      Two phonograph records of the 1969 New York State School Music Association (NYSSMA) Music Festival. Orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - NYSSMA Suffolk Sectional Music Festival, 1966 Nov 19; 2 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7, Box Record Covers 1)
      Two phonograph records of the New York State School Music Association (NYSSMA) Suffolk Sectional Music Festival on November 19, 1966.
    - Russell Oberlin and Joseph Iadone; John Dowland: Lute Songs, 1958; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7)
      Phonograph record of the album John Dowland: Lute Songs released in 1958 by Experiences Anonymes (EA-0034), featuring Russell Oberlin (countertenor) and Joseph Iadone (lute – Hartt Faculty).
    - Paul Olefsky and Walter Hautzig; Sonatas for Cello and Piano, Circa 1969; 1 Phonographs With inscribed record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7)
      Phonograph record of the album Sonatas for Cello and Piano released circa 1969 by Monitor Records (MC 2116/MCS 2116), featuring Paul Olefsky (cello) and Walter Hautzig (piano) performing Brahm's Sonata in E Minor, Op. 38 for Cello and Piano and Sonata in F Major, Op. 99 for Cello and Piano. The record cover includes a signed inscription from Olefsky to Moshe Paranovn dated March 25, 1969.
    - Moshe Paranov; Juke Box Jingles, 1952 Feb 8; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7)
      Phonograph recording of Juke Box Jingles by Moshe Paranov, recorded by WTIC on February 8, 1952.
    - Moshe Paranov and Supporting Cast; WTIC recording, 1938 Nov 4; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7)
      Phonograph record of Moshe Paranov and a supporting cast, conducted by Moshe Paranov, recorded by WTIC on November 4, 1938.
    - Frank Pettingell; Dickens Duets, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7)
      Phonograph record of the album Dickens Duets read by Frank Pettingell, produced/directed by Arthur Luce Klein, and released by Spoken Arts (741).
    - Richard Provost; Guitar: Old and New World, 1969; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7)
      Phonograph record of the album Guitar: Old and New World released in 1969 by Ars Nova-Ars Antiqua (LCCN R68-3570), featuring Richard Provost (guitar – Hartt faculty) performing Suite No. 3 in D Minor by Robert De Visée (first recording), Sonata No. 2 Op. 15 by Fernando Sor, Sonatina Op. 51 by Lennox Berkeley, and Sonata by Alexander Bellow (first recording). Recording engineer was Nina Paranov Fagan.
    - Thomas Putsche; In the Dark Pine Wood, undated; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7)
      Phonograph recording of In the Dark Pine Wood by Thomas Putsche.
    - Florica Remetier and the Hartt Symphony, 1955 Mar 27; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7)
      Phonograph recording of Florica Remetier and the Hartt Symphony, conducted by Moshe Paranov, recorded on March 27, 1955.
    - Saint Ann's Church Choir; Rejoice, Circa 1962; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7)
      Phonograph record of the album Rejoice released Circa 1962 by MZ Records (MZLP 5002), featuring Saint Ann's Church Choir.
    - Donald Sinta with Nelita True; American Music, 1965; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7)
      Phonograph record of the album American Music released in 1965 by Mark Educational Recordings (MRS 22868), featuring Donald Sinta (alto saxophone – Hartt faculty) with Nelita True (piano).
    - Spring Choral Festival of Secondary Schools with Hartt Symphony Orchestra; The Messiah, 1958 Apr 27; 2 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7)
      Phonograph recording of the Spring Choral Festival of Secondary Schools, with the Hartt Symphony Orchestra on April 27, 1958 at the Bushnell Memorial Hall, performing The Messiah by George Frederick Handel with Moshe Paranov conducting.
    - Spring Choral Festival of Secondary Schools with Hartt Symphony Orchestra, 1961 Apr 30; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 7)
      Phonograph recording of the Spring Choral Festival of Secondary Schools, with the Hartt Symphony Orchestra on April 30, 1961 at the Bushnell Memorial Hall, performing The Sons of Light by Ralph Vaughan Williams and Litany in B Flat, K. 125 with Moshe Paranov conducting.
    - Spring Choral Festival of Secondary Schools with Hartt Symphony Orchestra, 1963 Apr 28; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph recording of the Tenth Anniversary Spring Choral Festival of Secondary Schools, with the Hartt Symphony Orchestra on April 28, 1963 at the Bushnell Memorial Hall, performing Canticle of the Sun by Howard Boatwright, Song of Destiny by Johannes Brahms, and Magnificat by Dietrich Buxtehude with Moshe Paranov conducting.
    - Spring Choral Festival of Secondary Schools with Hartt Symphony Orchestra, 1964 Apr 26; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph recording of the Spring Choral Festival of Secondary Schools, with the Hartt Symphony Orchestra on April 26, 1964 at the Bushnell Memorial Hall, performing Mass in G by Franz Schubert and Gloria by Francis Pouleng with Moshe Paranov conducting.
    - Spring Choral Festival of Secondary Schools with Hartt Symphony Orchestra, 1968 Apr 28; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph recording of the Spring Choral Festival of Secondary Schools, with the Hartt Symphony Orchestra on April 28, 1968 at the Bushnell Memorial Hall, performing Mass in E Flat Major by Franz Schubert with Moshe Paranov conducting.
    - Trinity Church Choir, 1956 Dec 24; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph recording Trinity Church Choir on December 24, 1956.
    - Bertram Turetzky; Bertram Turetzky: The Virtuoso Doublebass, 1965; 1 Phonographs With inscribed record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph record of the album Bertram Turetzky: The Virtuoso Doublebass released in 1965 by Medea Records (MCLP 1001), featuring Bert Turetzky (double bass), with assisting artists Nancy Turetzky (flute and alto flute), Daniel Kobialka (violin), and Tele Lesbines (percussion). The record cover includes a signed inscription from Bertram Turetzky to Moshe Paranov dated June 1966.
    - McCoy Tyner and Jackie McLean; It's About Time, 1985; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph record of the album It's About Time released in 1985 by Blue Note (BT 85102, LCCN 99576067), featuring McCoy Tyner and Jackie McLean (Hartt faculty).
    - Bela Urban, Virginia Urban, and Marcel Hubert, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph record of the album released by Classic Editions (CE 1005), featuring Hartt faculty members Bela Urban, Virginia Urban, and Marcel Hubert performing Sonata for Violin and Cello by Maurice Ravel, II Pleure Dans Mon Coeur by Claude Debussy, Second Sonata for Violin and Piano by Darius Milhaud, and Le Jardinier de Samos by Jacques Ibert.
    - Bela Urban, Virginia Urban, and Simeon Bellison, undated; 1 Phonographs With inscribed record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph record of the album released by Classic Editions (CE 1002), featuring Bela Urban (Hartt faculty), Virginia Urban (Hartt faculty), and Simeon Bellison performing Trio for Clarinet, Violin, and Piano by Aram Khachaturian and Sonata for Violin and Piano by Maurice Ravel. The record cover includes a signed inscription from Bela Urban to Alfred Fuller.
    - Aristid Von Wurtzler; Aristid von Wurtzler, Harpist, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph record of the album Aristid von Wurtzler, Harpist released by American Stereophonic Corporation (ASCO A112), featuring Aristid von Wurtzler (harp – Hartt faculty).
    - Donald Voorhees and the Symphony Orchestra; Music for Listening, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph record of the album Music for Listening released by Allied Record Sales Company (LP-3001), featuring Donald Voorhees conducting a Symphony Orchestra.
    - WCCC; University of Hartford SP07 Announcements, 1960 Apr 29; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph record of University of Hartford radio announcements recorded by WCCC. Contains cuts 1-14.
    - William C. Willett and James Staples; Recital Music for Clarinet, 1970; 1 Phonographs With inscribed record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph record of the album Recital Music for Clarinet released by Mark Educational Recordings (MRS 32638) in 1970, featuring William C. Willet (clarinet – Hartt faculty) and James Staples (piano). The record cover includes a signed inscription from Willett to Moshe Paranov.
    - WTIC; Story of the Christ Child, 1939 Dec 24; 4 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Four phonograph records of Story of the Christ Child recorded by WTIC.
    - WTIC; Vincent Coffin's Address and Kinsella-Sharpe Hearing, 1959 Jan 5; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 8)
      Phonograph record of Vincent Coffin's Address and the Kinsella-Sharpe Hearing recorded by WTIC, dated January 5, 1959.
    - Youth String Orchestra, 1952 Mar 30; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 9)
      Phonograph record of the Youth String Orchestra performing at Carnegie Hall under the conduction of Moshe Paranov on March 30, 1952.
    - Unidentified [Hartt Opera Theater Guild?]; Sister Angelica, undated; 7 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 9)
      Seven phonograph records of a performance of Sister Angelica. This may be a Hartt Opera Guild production and could be a duplicate copy of their 1945 performance.
    - Unidentified [Irene Kahn and/or Isadore Freed?]; Pooka Dance, 1948 Apr 19; 3 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 9)
      Three phonograph records of Pooka Dance. The original record sleeve was labelled with "Kahn," but the label on the first disc lists "Freed" as the recorder. It is not clear if, or which of, these names reflect the performer, owner, and/or recording engineer.
    - Unidentified, undated; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 9)
    - Unidentified, undated; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 9)
    - Unidentified, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 9)
  - 16-inch Transcription Discs, 1945-1961, undated
    - Your Box at the Opera, 1945 Nov 11 - 1957 Oct 22, undated (Box 16in. Transcription Discs 1, Folder 1-20, Box 16in. Transcription Discs 2, Folder 1-19, Box 16in. Transcription Discs 3, Folder 1-18, Box 16in. Transcription Discs 4, Folder 1-15)
    - WDRC - University of Hartford Interviews, undated (Box 16in. Transcription Discs 4, Folder 16-17)
    - WTIC - University of Hartford Arts and Music Campagin, 1961 Nov (Box 16in. Transcription Discs 4, Folder 18)
    - WTIC - University of Hartford, cuts 1-9 and 10-19, undated (Box 16in. Transcription Discs 4, Folder 19)
    - Theater of Melody, 1947, undated (Box 16in. Transcription Discs 5, Folder 1-3)
    - Travelers Broadcasts, undated (Box 16in. Transcription Discs 5, Folder 4-6)
      Contains three discs. One contains various songs and performers. The second features Julius Patzak and Gerhard Pechner. The third features Julius Patzak
    - Music from the World of Romance, 1947 Aug 10 (Box 16in. Transcription Discs 5, Folder 7)
    - Mary Howard Recordings, 1945 Jun 24, undated (Box 16in. Transcription Discs 5, Folder 8-9)
      Contains two discs, the first Onelia Fineschi with EIAK under Gabriele Simionetti. The second has various songs (some unidentified).
    - Freedom's People, undated (Box 16in. Transcription Discs 5, Folder 10-12)
    - Unidentified, 1950, undated (Box 16in. Transcription Discs 5, Folder 13-17)
- Ephemera, 1938-1976, undated
  This series consists of ephemera such as programs, letters, notes, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets that were found inside record covers with the recordings. Record covers can be found in the Recordings series.
  The series is arranged in alphabetical order by the last name of the performer (or event name) of the recording in which the ephemera was found.
  - Harold Bauer; Harold Bauer Plays Chopin, 1970; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Harold Bauer; Johannes Brahms, Sonata in F Minor, Op. 5, undated; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Harold Bauer; Schumann, Fantasiestucke (Opus 12), undated; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Mario Davidovsky and Barbara Kolb, 1976; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Luiz De Moura Castro; Villa-Lobos and Liszt, undated; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Raya Garbousova; Cello Melodies, undated; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Irene Jacobi and the Coolidge Quartet; Frederick Jacobi, Hagiographa, 1938; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Laurel Music Camp Orchestra, 1954; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Ted Melyan; unidentified, undated; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
    File contains a single record sleeve with an inscription to R. De Maria, signed by Ted Melyan. It is unclear which album was originally in this sleeve.
  - New England Preparatory School Music Festival Chorus, with the Cambridge Festival Orchestra, 1964 Apr; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - New York Sectional Orchestra, 1953 Nov 21; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Russell Oberlin and Joseph Iadone; John Dowland: Lute Songs, 1958; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Saint Ann's Church Choir; Rejoice, Circa 1962; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Freidrich Schorr; Shumann Liederkreis, Opus 39, undated; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Theater of Melody, 1947; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - WTIC - University of Hartford Arts and Music Campaign, 1961 Nov 16; 1 Folders (Box Shared Document Box 1)
  - Your Box at the Opera (Box Shared Oversized 2)
- Duplicates, 1961-1986; undated
  This series consists of duplicate copies of recordings in the collection.
  - Harold Bauer; Moonlight Sonata Part 3 and Gavotte in F Major, undated; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 9)
  - The Contemporary Chamber Players of the University of Chicago, undated; 2 Phonographs duplicates, with record covers 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 9, Box Record Covers 1)
  - Hartt College Symphony Orchestra; MENC Eastern Division Concert, 1969; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 9, Box Record Covers 1)
  - Igor Kipnis, Jay Gottlieb, and Ensemble InterContemporain; Barbara Kolb: Toccata, Appello, Soundings, 1986; 1 Phonographs With inscribed record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 9, Box Record Covers 1)
    The record cover includes a signed inscription from Kolb to Ethel Bacon.
  - Laurel Music Camp Concert, 1966 Jul 1; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 9, Box Record Covers 1)
  - Robert Maxwell; The Broadcaster: A Symphonic Suite, 1961 Nov 27; 2 Phonographs duplicates, with record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 9, Box Record Covers 1)
  - Richard Provost; Guitar: Old and New World, 1969; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box Shared 12 in. Phonograph Record Box 1, Box Record Covers 1)
  - Spring Choral Festival of Secondary Schools with Hartt Symphony Orchestra, 1961 Apr 30, 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box Shared 12 in. Phonograph Record Box 1, Box Record Covers 1)
  - Bertram Turetzky; Bertram Turetzky: The Virtuoso Doublebass, 1965; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box Shared 12 in. Phonograph Record Box 1, Box Record Covers 1)
  - Bela Urban, Virginia Urban, and Simeon Bellison, undated; 1 Phonographs With library record cover 12in. (Box Shared 12 in. Phonograph Record Box 1, Box Record Covers 1)
  - William C. Willett and James Staples; Recital Music for Clarinet, 1970; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box Shared 12 in. Phonograph Record Box 1, Box Record Covers 1)